Why are these strange words everywhere?
为什么到处都是这些奇怪的词语？
Oh, did you think it was Latin?
哦，你以为它是拉丁文吗？
What if I told you Lorem wasn't a part of any language?
如果我告诉你 Lorem 不是任何语言的一部分呢？
Okay, so it's just nonsense
好吧，其实就是一些
words made to look like Latin.
看起来像拉丁文的无意义词语。
But no, ipsum IS Latin. It means ‘itself’.
但事实并非如此，ipsum 就是拉丁文。 它的意思是“它本身”。
So is dolor sit amet.
所以 dolor sit amet。
It means [because it’s] ‘pain he loves’.
意思是[因为这是]“他所喜爱的痛苦”。
What Lorem ipsum actually is,
Lorem ipsum 实际上
is a far stranger series of decisions that lived beyond anyone's expectations
是一个更为奇怪的决定，它 超越了任何人的预期，
to become the most famous nonsense text in the world.
成为了 世界上最著名的无意义文本。
And, an unsolved mystery.
而且，还有一个未解之谜。 一切
It starts with one man.
始于一个人。
I'm off to Virginia to meet him.
我要去弗吉尼亚州见他。
So here's the situation.
情况是这样的。
Today, Lorem ipsum is filler text used in websites, labels, templates,
如今，Lorem ipsum 是一种 用于网站、标签、模板等
basically anywhere words need to go.
任何需要放置文字的地方的占位文本。
The point is that it's English- looking nonsense
关键是，它 看起来像是英文的无意义文字，
so people don't get distracted by the meaning of the words
这样人们就不会被 文字的含义分散注意力，
and can just focus on the design.
而可以专注于设计本身。
And it pops up everywhere.
它无处不在。
But this is only the end of the timeline.
但这只是时间线的终点。
We can at least trace it to 1987. With the rise of Macs and personal computers,
我们至少可以追溯到 1987 年。随着 Mac 和个人电脑的兴起，
one of the first text programs to use actual paper page formatting
最早 使用实际纸张页面格式的文本程序之一
was Aldus Pagemaker.
是 Aldus Pagemaker。
And its third version had this strange filler text for all to use.
第三版中还包含一段奇怪的 填充文字，供所有人使用。
Of course, most people thought it was meaningless text. It’s designed to be.
当然，大多数人认为这只是毫无 意义的文字。 它的设计初衷就是如此。
But when someone asks Before &amp; After design magazine about it
但当有人就 此事询问《前后设计》杂志，
and they give that reply, a mysterious man writes back.
而他们也给出了这样的答复时， 一位神秘男子回复了他们。
No, everyone is wrong.
不，所有人都错了。
Lorem ipsum IS Latin, slightly jumbled,
Lorem ipsum IS Latin, slightly jumbled, the
the remnants of a passage from Cicero's De Finibus, a book from 2,000 years ago.
remplens of a passage from Cicero's De Finibus, a book from 2,000 years ago.
His name is Richard McClintock, and he's a former Latin
他的名字叫理查德·麦克林托克， 曾是
professor and publications director at Hampden-Sydney College.
汉普顿-悉尼学院的拉丁语教授和出版主任。 而这正是
Which is exactly where we're headed.
我们前进的方向。
Dr. McClintock? - Hello.
麦克林托克博士？ - 你好。
Hello.
你好。
I brought you a rose off of our rose bush.
我从 自家玫瑰丛里摘了一朵玫瑰给你。
Oh, thank you so much. - You’re welcome.
哦，非常感谢。 - 不客气。
It’s beautiful. It's so nice to meet you. - Good to meet you.
很美丽。 很高兴见到你。 很 高兴见到你。
Where did you see Lorem ipsum in that first instance?
你 第一次看到 Lorem ipsum 是在哪里？
Well, as a graphic designer, I saw it a lot in the layout programs
作为一名平面设计师， 我在
that we used to make the publications for Hampden-Sydney.
我们为 汉普顿-悉尼学院制作出版物时使用的排版软件中经常看到这种情况。
I was looking at it one day
有一天我看着它，突然
and realized it didn't look as though it was entirely gibberish.
意识到它看起来并不 完全是胡言乱语。
There was this unusual word consectetur.
有一个不常见的词 consectetur。
Do you have like an English word analogy?
你有没有类似英语单词的例子？ 这种事到底
Like how rare is it?
有多罕见？
It's the kind of word that they would-
这是那种
you would put on an SAT exam.
你会在SAT考试中遇到的词。
Like punctilious. - That sort of thing, yes ma’am.
一丝不苟。 是的， 女士，就是那种事。
I looked it up in the dictionary.
我查了字典。
No... - I do see consecta-
不…… ——我确实看到了 consecta——
Oh, that's. You're right.
哦，那是。 你说得对。
Thank you. Glad somebody’s paying attention.
谢谢。 很 高兴有人注意到这一点。
To pursue eagerly, to strive after, endeavor to gain,
热切地追求，努力追求， 努力获得，
Neque quisquam est qui dolorem ipsum,
Neque quisquam est qui dolorem ipsum,
quia dolor sit, amet, consectetur, adipisci velit.
quia dolor sat, amet, consectetur, adipisci velit。
Cicero De Fin 1.10.32.
西塞罗《论终结》1.10.32。
Then somebody writes in to Before &amp; After,
然后有人写信给“ 前后对比”
someone wrote in,
栏目，说：“
I'm curious as to the Latin that you have hidden in some of your articles.
我很好奇你们 在一些文章中隐藏的拉丁文是什么意思。”
It usually says Lorem ipsum dolor. And the editor of the magazine
它通常说 Lorem ipsum dolor。 杂志编辑
said basically it was just gibberish.
说，这基本上就是一堆胡言乱语。
And I said, he's not right about that.
我说，他在这点上错了。
And so of course I wrote him a letter and told him that it was
因此，我当然给他写了一封信， 告诉他这
in fact an excerpt from Cicero's De finibus bonorum et malorum.
实际上是西塞罗的《论 至善与至恶》中的一段摘录。
So you just wrote in thinking no one would care except this magazine and you
所以你写信来是觉得 除了这家杂志和你（你纠正了他们的错误）之外，没有人会在意
who had corrected them. - Right.
。 - 正确的。
I just did it as a pedant, you know...
我当时只是出于吹毛求疵才这么做的，你知道……
But it just- it took off,
但没想到它竟然火了，简直太
it was insane.
疯狂了。
So now we have some origins.
现在我们掌握了一些起源信息。 公元前
In the summer of 45 BCE, a year before Caesar is killed,
45 年夏天 ，即凯撒被杀的前一年，
Cicero writes De finibus bonorum et malorum,
西塞罗撰写了《De finibus bonorum et malorum》，
comparing pros and cons of popular philosophies.
比较了 流行哲学的利弊。
Now, the book itself isn't that notable.
然而，这本书本身并没有什么特别之处。
Had you read it before? I had not. - Oh, okay.
你之前读过吗？ 我没有。 - 哦好的。
I have still actually not read the entire thing.
我其实还没看完。
Oh! It sounds like it's not compelling reading.
哦！ 听起来好像没什么吸引力。
Still, as one of the most famous writers in history, arguably
不过，作为历史上最著名的作家之一 ，可以说
responsible for the Renaissance, the Enlightenment, and our enduring love
对文艺复兴、 启蒙运动以及我们
for the Roman Empire, it's no surprise we've saved many Cicero
对罗马帝国的持久热爱负有责任，因此，在过去的2000年里， 我们保存了许多西塞罗的
works over the past 2000 years.
作品也就不足为奇了。
But immediately there are complications.
但紧接着就出现了问题。
Lorem ipsum was not just copied down.
Lorem ipsum 不仅仅是复制下来的。
The passage Richard found is Book 1, Chapter 10, Sections 32 to 33.
理查德找到的段落是第一卷第十章第 32至33节。
The ‘-ng’ is a big change because that's an English thing and not a Latin thing.
“-ng”是一个很大的变化，因为这是 英语的特征，而不是拉丁语的特征。 在拉丁语中，
You would never see a word ending with ‘-ng’ in Latin.
你永远不会看到 以“-ng”结尾的单词。
No, and they took the V off
不，他们把
‘velit’, which so it means-
“velit”中的 V 去掉了，所以它的意思
it doesn’t mean ‘he wishes’ anymore,
不再是“他希望”，而
it just means elit.
只是“精英”的意思。
To demonstrate just how messed up it is,
为了说明 这有多么荒谬，
the English translation of Cicero's original sentence reads:
西塞罗原句的英文翻译 是：
Nor is there anyone who pursues or desires
也没有人会去追求或渴望
to obtain pain itself, simply because it is pain.
获得痛苦本身，仅仅 因为它是痛苦。
In 2012, a Latin scholar at the University of Cambridge
2012年，剑桥大学的一位拉丁语学者
attempted to translate Lorem ipsum into English and got:
尝试将Lorem ipsum翻译 成英语，结果得到：
Rrow itself, let it be sorrow;
Row itself, let it be sorrow;
let him love it, let him pursue it, ishing for its acquisitiendum.
让他爱它，让他追求它， 渴望得到它。
(Auto subbing didn’t stand a chance.)
（自动字幕毫无胜算。）
But even if Lorem ipsum’s been tampered with, at least we have its origin.
但即使 Lorem ipsum 已被 篡改，至少我们还能找到它的来源。  《
Before &amp; After magazine publishes a correction,
前后对比》杂志 刊登了一则更正声明，使用了
Lorem Oopsum, and quotes Richard's fax.
Lorem Oopsum 文本，并引用了理查德的传真。
Lorem ipsum is Latin.
Lorem ipsum 是拉丁文。
What I find remarkable is that this text has been the industry’s
令我感到惊讶的 是，自
standard dummy text ever since some printer in the 1500s
16 世纪某个印刷商
took it a galley of type and scrambled it to make a type specimen book.
将这段文字从一排铅字中打乱， 制作成一本字体样本册以来，它一直是业界的标准示例文本。
This is the narrative now repeated by almost every source on Lorem ipsum.
这是现在 几乎所有关于 Lorem ipsum 的资料来源都在重复的说法。
The narrative.
叙述。
See, I thought this video would be my usual process.
你看，我原以为这个视频会像往常一样记录我的制作 过程。
Research, talk to experts, report back.
研究、咨询专家、汇报结果。
But soon I realized all the Lorem ipsum websites were wrong.
但很快我就意识到所有关于 Lorem ipsum 的网站都是错误的。
And then I realized a complete history of Lorem Ipsum doesn't exist.
然后我意识到， Lorem Ipsum 的完整历史记录并不存在。
There is no paper. There is no expert.
没有纸张。 没有专家。
It's on page 34 of a book that no one in their right mind would actually open.
它在第34页，而正常人 根本不会去翻开那本书。
So where on earth did they find it?
他们究竟是从哪里找到它的？
If you can dig out something definitive, this story could get so much traction.
如果你能找到一些确凿的证据， 这个故事可能会引起很大的关注。 就这样，
And that's when this went from me
事情从我
making a video to me conducting a full research investigation.
制作视频变成了我 进行全面的调查研究。
Let's start here.
我们就从这里开始吧。
Every source I see on Lorem ipsum says - Has that same
我看到的关于 Lorem ipsum 的所有资料都说 ——
It was invented in the 1500s. - remote error.
它发明于 16 世纪。 远程错误。
Every result you click on, on
你点击的每一个谷歌搜索结果，都会
Google says with great confidence
非常自信地告诉你，
it was invented by an anonymous typesetter in the 1500s.
这是16世纪一位匿名排字工发明的 。 是的
Yes. And that's all my fault.
。 这一切都是我的错。
Oh, no!
哦，不！
You were writing in because you're specifically
你 写信来是因为你专门
trying to correct Lorem ipsum, and then you just added that-
想纠正 Lorem ipsum， 然后你又添加了那个——
Yes. - Added that in.
是的。 ——我后来加上去了。
I actually never set out to become the world expert on this subject.
其实我从未想过要成为 这方面的世界专家。
I just wanted things to be right.
我只是希望一切都能顺利进行。
And this is all kind of happened around me.
这一切都发生在 我身边。
Kind of like the person in Charlie Brown
有点像《 查理·布朗》里那个无论走到哪里
who had a cloud over his head everywhere he went.
头上都顶着一团云的人 。
And here I am, making the cloud a rainstorm above your head.
而我，正在 你头顶上制造一场暴雨。
Well, you definitely correct for that fault because of what you discover next.
嗯，你肯定会 因为接下来的发现而纠正这个错误。 直到
It was only later when I went back to the book to look at it
后来 我翻回那本书仔细查看，
and physically turned the page, that all of a sudden it clicked
并实际翻到那一页时， 我才突然意识到那是
that it was that particular page and not any just regular text.
特定的一页， 而不是普通的文本。
Shall we go see the book itself? - Okay.
我们去看看这本书吧？ - 好的。
I'd love to see. And was it in this library that-
我很想看看。 是不是就 在这座图书馆里？就是
It was in this library. - Wow.
在这座图书馆里。 - 哇。
And this very copy of the book.
而这本书正是如此。
H. Rackham, M.A.
H. Rackham, M.A.
Published in 1914.
1914 年出版。Neque
Neque porro quisquam est qui do-
porro quisquam est qui do-
which it splits the word.
它将单词分开。
And then there is a page which starts off
然后有一个页面以
Lorem ipsum quia dolor sit amet,
Lorem ipsum quia dolor sat amet,
consectetur, adipisci velit.
consectetur, adipisci velit 开头。
That's incredible.
那真是难以置信。
So with your discovery of the 1914 Rackham book,
所以，在你发现了 1914 年的 Rackham 书籍之后，
I decided to go on my own discovery because I wanted to double
我决定自己也进行一番调查， 因为我想反复
and just triple check that Lorem ipsum had not existed before then.
确认 Lorem ipsum 在那之前是否真的存在过。
I actually was able to find dictionaries
实际上，我 找到了一些 19 世纪的词典，其中也
that actually have a dolorem ipsum cutoff as well, from the 1800s.
包含了 dolorem ipsum 截断符。
So this English one is from 1829.
所以这个英文版本出自1829年。
If you look under their definition of the word ‘eo’,
如果你查看他们对 “eo”一词的定义，会发现是“
Eeyo? - Ayo.
Eeyo？” - 哎哟。
Eo. - Therefore.
Eo。 - 所以。
Look right at this line here.
请看这里这条线。
Neque porro quisquam est, qui do- and then lorem ipsum
Neque porro quisquam est, qui do- 然后 lorem ipsum quia
quia dolor sit, amet. - Right.
dolor sat, amet。 - 正确的。
I thought this was very intriguing.
我觉得这非常有趣。
And then this other one - It is indeed.
还有另一个 ——确实如此。
is this German one from 1887.
这是1887年的德语版本。
And this actually, same word you looked for.
而且，这实际上就是你要找的那个词。
Look it says: Neque porro quisquam est, qui do- lorem ipsum.
看上面写着：Neque porro quisquam est, qui dolorem ipsum。
So I found these and I got excited.
我找到了这些，非常兴奋。
But then when I looked further, they do both just cut off after only one sentence.
但当我进一步查看时，发现它们都只说了 一句话就戛然而止了。
And I do think someone is very unlikely to have the phrase Lorem
而且我认为，不太可能有人
ipsum because of the cutoff in one of these dictionaries,
因为 词典中的某个部分被截断而找到“Lorem ipsum”这个短语，
and then had to go find another book to get the rest of the excerpt.
然后不得不去另一本书中 查找剩余的摘录。
I do think evidence still stands for the 1914 version.
我认为 1914年的版本仍然有证据支持。
But the other thing I went looking for,
但我寻找的另一件事，
the other angle I wanted to try, was looking for just any dummy text
我想尝试的另一个角度 ，是寻找在
that was used before Lorem ipsum, just to see if it would come up
Lorem ipsum 之前使用的任何占位文本， 看看它是否会
in some archive of that.
在某个存档中出现。
That's when I found the direct ancestor to Lorem Ipsum.
那时我找到了 Lorem Ipsum 的直接祖先。
Centuries ago, typographers used to copy a juicier Cicero quote.
几个世纪前，排版员常常 抄录西塞罗一句更精彩的名言。
The start of a speech
演讲开始，
exposing the senator Catiline for plotting to overthrow the government.
揭露参议员卡提林密谋 推翻政府。
Quousque tandem abutere, Catilina, patientia nostra?
Quousque tandem abutere， Catilina，耐心吗？
It was so common in the 17
这种做法在 17
and 1800s, that it literally changed the shape of the capital letter Q
和 18 世纪非常普遍，
as typographers competed to make their tails longer and more impressive.
以至于印刷商竞相使大写字母 Q 的 尾巴更长更醒目，从而彻底改变了字母 Q 的形状。
I found all of these from what I was really looking for, which was like
这些都是 我真正想找的东西，就像
an archive, really cataloging all the type specimens at the time.
一个档案库，里面详细记录了 当时所有的模式标本。
And that is this book. Daniel Berkeley Updike's Printing Types.
这就是这本书。 丹尼尔·伯克利·厄普代克的印刷字体。 这本书
It is so well done and so rigorously documented,
写得太好了， 资料也非常详实，
I got lost in that book for a very long time. But when you comb through the more
我读了很久都沉浸其中 。 但当你仔细翻阅
than 200 illustrations in the book, there is absolutely nothing
书中 200 多幅插图时，
besides the Catalina quote and English quotes or prayers.
除了卡特琳娜的引言 和英文引言或祈祷文之外，什么也没有。 就是这样。
What's also interesting is that this book was published in 1922.
有趣的是， 这本书出版于1922年。
To me, this was also useful
对我来说，这也有助于我们
to see that Lorem ipsum had not been documented prior to 1922.
了解Lorem ipsum在 1922年之前并没有相关记载。
The biggest thing is that the whole concept of dummy
最重要的 是，虚拟文本的概念
text did not happen until the middle of the 20th century.
直到20世纪中期才出现。
Oh, and why was that?
哦，这是为什么呢？
There was no way to do dummy text in those days because it was all lead type.
那时候没办法做占位文本， 因为全是铅字。 排版
A page of type would probably take the better part of half an hour to set.
一页文字大概需要 半个小时。
I see, so you're saying there's also kind of a purpose
我明白了，所以你的意思是说，它之前没有出现 也是有目的
driven or history reason why it wouldn't have existed earlier?
性或历史性的原因吗 ？
It would be a waste of time to set up dummy text, basically, yes.
设置 占位文本基本上是浪费时间，没错。
But in the timeline of Lorem ipsum, we still have a huge gap
但在 Lorem ipsum 的时间线上，
From 1914 to 1987.
从 1914 年到 1987 年仍然存在巨大的空白。
So I attacked from the other direction
所以我从另一个方向入手，
and found the person who brought Lorem ipsum digital in Aldus Pagemaker.
找到了将 Lorem ipsum 数字版引入 Aldus Pagemaker 的人。
I was there at the beginning, pretty much.
我几乎从一开始就在那里。
They wanted a designer to be involved really early on.
他们希望设计师 很早就参与进来。
Do you mind giving an intro to what Aldus Pagemaker was?
您能否简要介绍一下 Aldus Pagemaker 是什么？
It was kind of the first page layout
它算是最早的页面布局
software. Before, you used a typewriter!
软件之一。 以前，你们用的是打字机！
When updating the next version of Page Maker,
在更新 Page Maker 的下一个版本时 ，
Laura remembered something from her design roots.
劳拉想起了她设计 生涯中的一些经历。
You know, production was expensive, you had to kind of figure it all out
你知道，生产成本很高， 你必须提前把所有事情都考虑周全
and spec it ahead of time.
并制定好规格。 比如说，
When I was designing a feature story, let's say, to layout the body text
当我设计一篇专题报道， 用来排版正文时，
Letraset made this rub down lettering and you'd get sheets of this stuff.
Letraset 出品了一种可摩擦的字母贴纸， 你会得到一整张这种贴纸。
And for the headline, you’d rub down individual letters.
至于标题， 你需要逐个字母进行打磨。
And for the body text you'd get a sheet of the Lorem ipsum text.
正文部分 则会提供一张 Lorem ipsum 文本。
So I decided that we should add it as one of the tools
所以我决定把它 作为
or the extras that you got when you got the program.
购买该程序时附带的工具或附加功能之一添加进去。
We've reached the heart of the mystery.
我们已经触及了谜团的核心。
Letraset is what I've been using to make all the fun text throughout the video.
视频中所有有趣的文字都是我用 Letraset 制作的。
In the 60s, these little dry transfer sheets transformed type design.
上世纪 60 年代，这些小小的干 转印纸改变了字体设计。
Before Letraset, designers had to stencil lettering by hand
在 Letraset 出现之前，设计师 要么得手工绘制模板字母，
or pay a professional printer for it.
要么得花钱请专业印刷商来制作。
But now, with just a bit of pressing,
但现在，只需稍加按压，
they could play with the core elements of text, like:
他们就可以玩转 文本的核心元素，例如：
Fonts. You know what that is.
字体。 你知道那是什么。
Leading, or vertical space.
前导空间，或垂直空间。
Tracking, or horizontal space.
跟踪，或水平空间。
Kerning, the individual spaces between letters.
字距调整，即字母之间单独的间距 。
People mix these last two up - track first, kern later.
人们常常把最后这两个概念混淆—— 先调整轨道，后调整字距。
And hierarchy. Headings versus subheadings versus body type.
还有等级制度。 标题、 副标题和正文类型。
It's this dense, long body type that really requires dummy text.
这种篇幅较长、内容密集的文本体 确实需要占位符文本。
And Letraset, the cutting-edge design tool, was already on it.
而尖端 设计工具 Letraset 早已着手开发相关产品。
What I did, I just took a sheet of this stuff
我当时的做法是， 拿了一张纸，在
and one afternoon really quickly typed it in.
一个下午 很快地把这些东西都打了出来。
Somebody was saying, we got to get this done.
有人说， 我们得赶紧把这事儿做完。
So I typed it in really fast and I know I made some typos.
所以我打字速度很快， 我知道我打错了一些字。
What were you thinking on that afternoon as you were typing it up?
那天下午你一边打字一边在想什么 ？
I was a little worried in the back of my mind, it's like
我心里有点担心 ，
is this copyright infringement? I hope not.
这会不会侵犯版权？ 我希望不是这样。
Fingers crossed.
但愿如此。
I made enough errors. I hope it's okay.
我犯的错误够多了。 希望没问题。
Could you have imagined that it would go on to like,
你能想象事情会 发展到这种地步吗？
Not in a million years, no.
绝对不可能，想都别想。
If you see a nibh, zzril, or consectetuer with an extra E,
如果您看到 nibh、zzril 或 consectetuer 带有一个额外的 E，
that's Laura's Lorem ipsum.
那就是 Laura 的 Lorem ipsum。
But of course,
当然，
how did Letraset get Lorem ipsum?
Letraset 是如何得到 Lorem ipsum 的呢？
That's why it would really be nice to talk to somebody from Letraset,
所以，如果能和 Letraset 的人聊聊就太好了，
to find out how they got to it in the first place is the real mystery.
弄清楚他们最初是如何获得这个专利的，这才 是真正的谜团。
In fact, Before &amp; After’s
事实上，《Before &amp; After》
original Lorem Oopsum correction ends with a note to Richard.
最初的 Lorem Oopsum 更正 以给 Richard 的一条注释结尾。
Thank you for uncovering the source of our dummy text.
感谢您找到了 我们示例文本的来源。
Even Letraset, the graphics giant who marketed it for 30 years,
就连 销售该产品长达 30 年的图形巨头 Letraset
didn't know what it was.
也不知道它是什么。
So began my search.
于是，我的寻觅之旅开始了。
I combed through Letraset Body Type from the 80s, the 70s,
我仔细查阅了 Letraset 从 80 年代、70 年代到
undated body type, catalog previews of body type,
未注明日期的字体类型、 字体类型目录预览、
ads for body type,
字体类型广告，
- Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet... - Lorem ipsum dolor...
- Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet... - Lorem ipsum dolor...
I sent dozens of emails to anyone remotely associated with Letraset.
我给所有与 Letraset 有任何关联的人发了几十封电子邮件 。
I searched online for every instance of Lorem ipsum since 1914,
我在线搜索了 自 1914 年以来所有出现 Lorem ipsum 的实例，
and ordered photocopies from libraries across the country.
并 从全国各地的图书馆订购了复印件。
Okay, no one's emailed me back, but I am closing in on an answer.
好吧，虽然还没有人回复我的邮件， 但我快要找到答案了。
For decades there are zero cases of Lorem ipsum,
几十年来， Lorem ipsum 从未出现过，
but it suddenly pops up around 1967 to 1970.
但在 1967 年 至 1970 年左右突然出现。
Usually as tiny text hiding in ads everywhere from the UK
通常以小字的形式 隐藏在从英国
to Mexico to Brazil.
到墨西哥再到巴西的各种广告中。
These are all of the earliest
这些是
instances of Lorem ipsum in print anywhere.
Lorem ipsum 最早的 印刷版本。
It's a Mexican clothing company, and it doesn't even say Lorem ipsum,
这是一家墨西哥服装公司， 它甚至没有写 Lorem ipsum，
but it says aliquam erat voluptat,
而是写了 aliquam erat voluptat，就在
Which comes right after it, right. - Exactly.
它后面，对吧。 - 确切地。
That’s fun. - It’s fun, right?
真有趣。 很 有趣，对吧？
This is from 1971, in Brazil.
这是1971年巴西的一段文字。 是的
Yeah. You've got a good eye for the Lorem ipsum.
。 你 对 Lorem ipsum 文本很有鉴赏力。
You can see the shape of it. - Right.
你可以看到它的形状。 - 正确的。 我发誓，
The very earliest one I could find, I swear,
我能找到的最早的广告
is a December 1967 ad for milk bottles in a British dairy magazine.
是 1967 年 12 月刊登 在英国一家乳制品杂志上的牛奶瓶广告。
We continue to discuss milking cows in every video.
我们 在每期视频中都会继续讨论挤牛奶这件事。
Using 1967 as a benchmark,
以 1967 年为基准，
I hunted for any Letraset sheets from the years just before.
我搜寻了 之前几年的 Letraset 字帖。 真是走了
And by sheer luck, I found THIS on ebay.
狗屎运，我在 eBay 上找到了这个。
This is by far the oldest Lorem ipsum I've ever seen,
这是 我迄今为止见过的最古老的 Lorem ipsum，
closing the timeline gap to just 50 years.
时间跨度缩短至仅 50 年。
And it's the longest one
而且它是最长的，
which allows for some line by line matching.
可以逐行 匹配。
I was able to find a copy of Letraset with Lorem ipsum on it from 1966.
我找到了一份 1966年版的Letraset字体集，里面有Lorem ipsum文本。
I'm going to do a little magic trick for you.
我要给你表演一个小 魔术。
I believe this is the first time Letraset’s Lorem ipsum
我相信这是 Letraset 的 Lorem ipsum 文本首次
has ever been entirely traced to a source.
被完全 追溯到其来源。
Take a look.
请看。
This sheet is one Lorem ipsum passage repeated three times.
这张表是一个 Lorem ipsum 段落，重复了三次。
We already know Lorem ipsum matches
我们已经知道 Lorem ipsum 与
De Finibus starting at the top of page 36.
De Finibus 从第 36 页顶部开始匹配。
So it's Lorem ipsum,
所以是 Lorem ipsum，
Lorem ipsum, and it all matches through the end of the page here.
Lorem ipsum，一直到 页面末尾都匹配。
From there it follows the whole page down to the end, nos amice et nebevol.
从那里开始，整页 一直写到结尾，nos amice et nebevol。
Then it jumps forward to page 56, starting with molestias access potest,
然后它跳到第 56 页， 从 molestias access potest 开始，
down to the end again with etiam mag quod cuis.
一直到结尾 etiam mag quod cuis。
Kooyis. - Cuis.
库伊斯。 - 美食。
It's modified, but it's definitely this whole page.
虽然有所修改， 但肯定就是这一整页内容。
Then we hop down to page 70, starting with guae ad amicos pertineren
然后我们跳到第 70 页， 从 guae ad amicos pertineren 开始，
down to sempitern aut diuturning timer.
一直到 sempitern aut diuturning timer。
And then go to page 118, starting with auam multa vitiose,
然后转到第 118 页，从 auam multa vitiose 开始，
down to nullion diciud putialenim depra et non.
一直到 nullion diciud putialenim depra et non。
This very, very dense text of Lorem ipsum comes
这段非常非常密集的 Lorem ipsum 文本
from four different pages of this book.
取自本书的四个不同页面。
What's also funny is there are some phrases in other languages.
更有趣的是， 其中一些短语来自其他语言。
Es muy fuerte. That is 100% Spanish,
Es muy fuerte. 那句话是百分之百的西班牙语，
and another one is salar le grand, which 100% is French.
另一句是 salar le grand， 那是百分之百的法语。
In fact, I even found where you would see
事实上，我甚至找到了
salar le grand, which is in talking about Salmo salar, which is salmon.
salar le grand 的出处，它是在谈论 Salmo salar，也就是鲑鱼的时候出现的。
Whoever is doing this had some fun with adding these portions.
制作这些内容的人似乎 在添加这些部分时玩得很开心。
I have been known to add things into dummy text when I’m using them myself.
我有时会在 自己使用示例文本时，往其中添加一些内容。
Oh, yeah. There you go.
哦，是的。 好了。
You can also see they're all ascending pages.
您还可以看到 它们都是升序排列的页面。
Someone was just leafing through every, you know, 20 or so pages
有人随意翻阅了大约 20 页内容，
and creating Lorem ipsum.
然后创建了 Lorem ipsum。 通过这种剖析，
You can see the thought process almost by doing this dissection.
你几乎可以看到其思考过程 。
And I have had other people tell me that it went on like this.
也有其他人 告诉我，事情就是这样发生的。
But no one ever bothered pointing out that it was the exact pages.
但从来没有人费心 指出，这正是原先的几页。 这
Which is the definitive proof that it's this book and not some other text.
足以证明是 这本书，而不是其他什么书。
Which, congratulations. - Thank you.
恭喜！ - 谢谢。
Now we know where these words came from, but not who or why.
现在我们知道了这些词语的来源， 但不知道是谁说的，也不知道为什么。
has been cold ever since Richard first wrote to Before &amp; After.
自从理查德 第一次给《Before &amp; After》杂志写信以来，关于 Letraset 出现之前的线索就一直没有进展。
Honestly I mean, if you can dig out something definitive, it will become like
说实话，我的意思是，如果你能挖掘出 一些确凿的证据，它就会在设计界引起
a minor pop culture sensation in the design world.
一股小小的流行文化热潮 。
Lorem ipsum is still a hot topic there.
Lorem ipsum 仍然是那里的热门话题。
Actually, to this day, designers still debate the whole practice
事实上，直到今天，设计师们 仍在争论
of placeholder text, which they call greeking.
占位符文本的整个做法， 他们称之为“希腊化”。   真是
Ironic.
讽刺。
Some call it a design crutch. Words are essential.
有人称之为设计 拐杖。 文字至关重要。
You need to evaluate your design together with the content,
你需要将设计 与内容结合起来评估，
and fit your visuals to the actual words on the page.
并使视觉效果 与页面上的实际文字相匹配。
Cause if you set an obituary in Comic Sans, you're insulting somebody.
因为如果你用 Comic Sans 字体写讣告 ，那就是在侮辱别人。
So I can see that point, but it's considerably outweighed
我明白这一点， 但这
by the practical purposes of the dummy text.
与 示例文本的实际用途相比，就显得微不足道了。
Others call it a helpful tool to start designing without the final words ready.
其他人则认为它是一个有用的工具，可以帮助人们在 最终定稿之前开始设计。
And it can help prevent design meetings from going off track with clients
这样可以防止设计会议因为 客户
caught up on exact wording.
纠结于确切的措辞而偏离主题。
Now it's a parallel process rather than a sequential process.
现在这是一个并行过程， 而不是顺序过程。
Now you know Typography 101 and form versus content,
现在你已经了解了 排版基础知识以及形式与内容的区别，
you've got the basics of graphic design.
你就掌握了平面设计的基础知识。
The thing is, even after finding all this and doing this dissection,
问题是，即使找到了所有这些， 并进行了这样的解剖，
I still don't know how- - You got from here to there.
我仍然不知道 ——你是如何从这里到那里的。
I had a bunch of emails out to people and heard nothing back,
我给很多人发了邮件，但都 没有收到回复。不过
but I had a little bit of a clue in that, by doing this work,
， 通过这项工作，我
You can tell that this was not the work of an amateur.
隐约觉得 这不是业余人士的作品。
The garbled text is done with a lot of care and knowledge.
这段乱码文字是 经过精心制作和运用专业知识的。
You can see
你可以从中看到
a lot of rational decisions about why it looks the way it does in there.
很多关于它外观为何如此的理性决策 。
They are making very careful additions, such as adding letters
他们非常谨慎地进行添加， 例如添加一些原本不会出现的字母
that wouldn’t- - The -ands and the -ngs, right.
——比如 -and 和 -ng，对吧。
The Y got stuck in because that's an English letter.
因为Y是英文字母，所以就卡住了。
See, the Latin alphabet isn't exactly like English.
你看，拉丁字母和 英语字母并不完全一样。
It doesn't use letters like J, K, Y, and Z,
它不使用 J、K、Y 和 Z 等字母，
while relying more on letters like Q, U, and M.
而更多地使用 Q、U 和 M 等字母。
If you look at the letters changed in Lorem ipsum, Q’s and M’s are removed,
如果你查看 Lorem ipsum 中更改的字母，你会发现 Q 和 M 被删除了，
while Y's are added. And words were removed surprisingly carefully.
而 Y 被添加进来了。 删除文字的过程出人意料地 细致。
The biggest change is that they left out the quia,
最大的变化 是他们省略了 quia，
that means because, which means that it doesn't make any sense.
意思是 because，这意味着 它没有任何意义。
So it was a very smart removal,
所以这是一次非常巧妙的删除，一次精准的
a surgical removal of that one word that creates meaning in the sentence.
手术式删除，删除了 句子中那个赋予意义的词。
And I think that may be why they took it out.
我觉得这可能就是 他们把它删掉的原因。
I mean, it sounds like someone who would have knowledge of both Latin
我的意思是，听起来像是既懂 拉丁语
and English and graphic design. - On a linguistic level.
、英语又懂平面设计的人。 - 从语言学层面来看。
Right.
正确的。
Which is a pretty narrow field, like expertise that you're looking for.
这算是一个相当狭窄的领域， 就像你正在寻找的专业技能一样。
Someone like you, basically.
基本上就是像你这样的人。
I think the fact that it is garbled Latin text,
我认为， 它是乱码拉丁文，
and that it has those other letters in a fairly
而且拉丁字母表中其他字母出现的
Latin-based alphabet amount of frequency, speaks to that
频率相当高，这 表明
it was done very, very carefully.
它是经过非常非常仔细的制作的。
And then, someone replied to my email.
然后，有人回复了我的邮件。
Thanks to the powers that be,
多亏了相关部门，
someone at Letraset emailed me back.
Letraset 公司有人回复了我的邮件。
And this is an email I would like to read to you.
我想把这封邮件读给你听。
This is from Dave Farey, one of the earliest designers at Letraset.
这是 Dave Farey 的原话，他是 Letraset 最早的设计师之一。
And he had a story.
他有一个故事。
At a marketing meeting sometime during 1966,
在 1966 年的一次市场营销会议上 ，
publicity design manager Colin Orchard mentioned that a sheet of dummy text
宣传设计经理科林·奥查德 提到，一张示例文本
would be useful for his work, and also for graphic designers generally.
对他的工作 以及一般的平面设计师都很有用。
They needed more expertise, but fortunately Letraset had developed
他们需要更多专业知识， 但幸运的是，Letraset
a strong relationship with the Saint Bride Printing Library,
与 圣布莱德印刷图书馆
and the head librarian, James Mosley.
及其馆长 James Mosley 建立了牢固的关系。
James was an academic who devoted his professional
詹姆斯是一位学者， 他毕生致力于
life to the history and contemporary use of printing and typography.
印刷和排版的历史和当代应用研究。
James realized that all type founders in Europe and the USA use their own
詹姆斯意识到， 欧洲和美国的所有字体创始人都使用他们自己
placeholder text in their own language. And he looked to an alternative,
语言的占位符文本。 于是他开始寻找替代方案，
as Latin was the core for 90% of all Western languages.
因为拉丁语是 90%西方语言的核心。
And then he goes on to say that Cicero's Catiline quote was too famous,
然后他又说， 西塞罗关于卡提利纳的引言太有名了，
so James found another Cicero quote and created Lorem ipsum.
所以詹​​姆斯找到了西塞罗的另一句 引言，并创作了 Lorem ipsum。
Letraset adopted the Lorem ipsum text copy as body type style in late 1966
Letraset 在 1966 年末或 1967 年初采用了 Lorem ipsum 文本作为正文样式，当时推出了
or early 1967, with two fonts, Universe and Times New Roman, adding six
Universe 和 Times New Roman 两种字体，
additional type styles by 1971.
到 1971 年又增加了六种字体样式。
Does he tell us why he chose that?
他有没有告诉我们他为什么选择这种样式？
He speculates. Probably it was that there was another Cicero quotation
他进行了推测。 可能是 因为之前已经引用过西塞罗的另一句名言
that had been used, so this was a great alternative
， 所以这句名言就成了很好的替代
Cicero choice, and it may have been garbled
选择， 而且可能
by more than one typesetter working at his bench since the 1500s.
自 16 世纪以来，不止一位排字工在他的工作台上把它弄错了。
Oh merciful heavens.
仁慈的上苍啊！
The recursive-
递归——
Richard’s mistake may have come full circle, but the rest of the story checks out.
理查德的错误或许兜了个圈子， 但故事的其他部分都说得通。
James was a librarian with heaps of old books,
詹姆斯是一位图书管理员， 拥有大量的旧书；他是
a historian fluent in French, Italian, German, and almost
一位精通法语、 意大利语、德语的历史学家，而且几乎可以
certainly Latin, and a world expert in typography.
肯定他还会拉丁语；他还是 世界级的排版专家。
I wish I made this video a year earlier.
我真希望一年前就拍了这个视频。
Sadly, James passed away in 2025.
令人遗憾的是，詹姆斯于 2025 年去世了。
But if anyone related to him or in general knows about the birth of Lorem ipsum, or
但如果有人与他有关，或者 了解 Lorem ipsum 的诞生，或者
if any historians want to help me document all this research, please email me.
有历史学家愿意帮助我记录 所有这些研究，请给我发电子邮件。
While we can't ask James himself,
虽然我们无法询问 James 本人，但
it feels very in the spirit of a type historian that we’re tracing
追溯他
his past thinking through the design choices he made.
过去的设计思路，了解 他所做的设计选择，这很符合字体历史学家的精神。
That's amazing.
太棒了。
You should’ve come by here two years ago.
你两年前就该来这里了 。 真
I can't believe you got this done.
不敢相信你居然完成了。
Thank you to Dave.
谢谢你，戴夫。
He ends the message with ‘Hoc est totem, amici’.
他 以“Hoc est totem, amici”结尾。
This is everything, friend.
朋友，这就是全部了。
I want to ask about how this whole journey has affected your life.
我想问问 这段旅程对你的生活产生了哪些影响。
Well, I generally like to hide in dark corners
嗯，我通常喜欢 躲在阴暗的角落里，
and this has been opening those dark corners up, because people
而这件事却把 这些阴暗的角落都打开了，因为
from all over the world have been emailing me for
来自世界各地的人们 已经给我发邮件
30 years is it now? - Wow.
30年了，不是吗？ - 哇。 在汉普顿-悉尼大学，
Enthusiastic students come up to me at Hampden-Sydney
热情的学生们走过来对我
and say, I finally get to meet you.
说：“我终于见到你了。” 这件事真的让
And it's just this completely baffles me.
我百思不得其解。
I warn you that this may not be the end of this for you.
我警告你， 这可能并非你事情的终结。
I'm ready.
我准备好了。
Bring it on.
来吧。
People send me pictures of Chipotle bags with Lorem ipsum on the side,
人们给我发来印有 Lorem ipsum 的 Chipotle 包装袋的照片 ，
and people send me places that Lorem ipsum has been
还有人给我发来 Lorem ipsum 出现
in The New York Times.
在《纽约时报》上的地方。   他
Pointed out that I have been in a Hallmark movie, of all things.
指出我竟然 出演过一部 Hallmark 电影。
Oh my gosh, it's Richard!
我的天哪，是理查德！
Oh yeah, the craziest part of all this
哦，对了，这一切最疯狂的地方
might be the fact that today,
或许在于，如今
Richard's own discovery has become the placeholder.
理查德自己的发现竟然 成了占位符。
That's because if you wanna go make Lorem ipsum, it's easy.
那是因为如果你想 制作 Lorem ipsum 文本，那很容易。
There are dozens of different Lorem ipsum sites.
有数十个不同的 Lorem ipsum 站点。
There are generators
有一些生成器
where you can make your own apocryphal dummy text.
可以让你制作自己的 伪经示例文本。
Telescope. Billions upon billions.
望远镜。 数十亿，数以亿计。
The carbon in our apple pies, descended from astronomers.
我们苹果派中的碳， 源自天文学家。
Post-ironic soft launch, ego death tacos,
后讽刺软启动，自我消亡的墨西哥卷饼，
Echo Park xiao long bao, doomer praxis.
回声公园小笼包，末日实践。
Cat ipsum dolor sit amet,
猫 ipsum dolor 坐着，
chase imaginary bugs. Chase imaginary bugs flop over hopped up on goofballs
追逐想象中的虫子。 追逐想象中的 虫子，它们像打了鸡血一样翻滚，
why must they do that. Hate dog snacks.
为什么非要这样做呢？ 讨厌狗零食。
I tell you, it's a cult.
我告诉你，那是一个邪教。
But the most common way
但最常见的做法
people do it is just by googling Lorem ipsum and copying the first result.
是直接在谷歌上搜索 Lorem ipsum，然后复制第一个搜索结果。
This is lipsum.com, and it's very handy.
这是lipsum.com，它非常方便。
It randomizes the text and even has different languages,
它会随机化文本， 甚至使用不同的语言，
but it puts the history before the lorem ipsum text itself.
但它将历史置于 lorem ipsum 文本本身之前。
So if you pull the first words from the website using code,
所以，如果你 用代码从网站提取第几个词，
or if you're just not looking closely, you get this explainer.
或者你只是没有仔细查看， 就会得到这个解释。
Lorem ipsum is
Lorem ipsum
simply dummy text of the printing and typesetting industry.
只是印刷 和排版行业的示例文本。
Then later,
后来，
Richard McClintock, a Latin professor at Hampden-Sydney College in Virginia,
弗吉尼亚州汉普顿-悉尼学院的拉丁语教授理查德·麦克林托克
looked up one of the more obscure Latin words, consectetur...
查阅了一个比较生僻的 拉丁词 consectetur……
First of all, this ruins the point of dummy text
首先，这破坏了 示例文本的意义，
because it's in English and still distracting.
因为它用的是英语， 而且仍然会分散注意力。
But most of all, it's just wrong.
但最重要的是，这完全是错误的。
It only has our very first story, the false 1500s origin.
它只收录了我们的第一个故事，即关于 16世纪起源的虚假故事。
So when people post this filler text, they're posting misinformation everywhere.
所以当人们发布这种填充文字时， 他们实际上是在到处传播错误信息。
So I actually still have one thing left to do.
所以，我其实还有一件事 要做。
I sent corrections out to all the Lorem ipsum generator sites with the wrong info,
我向所有 Lorem ipsum 生成器网站发送了更正信息，指出其中有错误，
and, they changed it!
他们都修改了！
The fact that now
现在
people recognize just the words Lorem ipsum,
人们能够将“ Lorem ipsum”（一种无意义的文本）识别
which are nonsense, as a signifier of dummy text
为虚拟文本的标志，这本身就挺
is kind of beautiful.
有意思的。
As a thing, right.
作为一件东西，没错。
Right. It is beautiful
正确的。 令人欣喜的是，原本
that something designed to be meaningless, has gained meaning.
设计成 毫无意义的事物，最终却获得了意义。
I think that is so human. - And significance, right.
我觉得这很人性化。 ——而且意义重大，对吧。
So look closely the next time you see Lorem ipsum in the wild.
所以下次 你在现实生活中看到 Lorem ipsum 时，请仔细观察。
Maybe you'll see our correction.
或许你会看到我们的更正。
Now we've made our own little notch in the ever-changing text of Lorem ipsum.
现在，我们在 不断变化的 Lorem ipsum 文本中留下了自己的印记。
I'm immensely impressed with your energy.
你的精力给我留下了深刻的印象。
Thank you.
谢谢。 你知道，
I got very invested myself in this journey, you know.
我全身心地投入到这段 旅程中。
I now feel like a Lorem ipsum hunter,
我现在感觉自己像个 Lorem ipsum 猎人，
like I care very deeply about this.
好像我对这件事非常在意。
I hereby pass the world expert title to you.
我在此将世界专家 称号授予你。
Oh, gosh. This is a heavy burden to carry.
哦，天哪。 这是个沉重的负担。 和
As always, in my description I've linked a Google doc with
往常一样，我在描述中附上了 一个包含
all my notes and sources from the video,
我所有笔记和视频来源的 Google 文档链接，
and I've linked my Patreon, where I've uploaded my full interview
我还附上了我的 Patreon 链接， 我在那里上传了我
with Richard because he's just so great and we nerd out so hard.
与 Richard 的完整采访，因为他太棒了， 我们聊得非常投入。
So that's totally free to watch, and also totally free
所以观看完全免费，
to sign up for my Patreon newsletter too.
注册我的 Patreon 新闻邮件也是完全免费的。
Or if you'd like to chip in to support my next videos, you can.
或者，如果您想资助 我制作下一个视频，也可以。
Thanks for watching.
感谢观看。